{"Topic": "Atomic Structure", "Subject": "General Knowledge", "Data": [{"Question": "Which of the following defines the Mass number of an atom?", "op1": "number of protons + number of electrons", "op2": "number of neutrons + number of electrons", "op3": "number of protons + number of neutrons", "op4": "number of electrons", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Who is credited with the discovery of electron?", "op1": "JJ Thomson", "op2": "James Chadwick", "op3": "Ernest Rutherford", "op4": "Niels Bohr", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "An atom has a mass number of 37 and atomic number 17. How many protons does it have?", "op1": "20", "op2": "17", "op3": "54", "op4": "21", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which of the following mostly accounts for the mass of an atom?", "op1": "neutrons", "op2": "neutron and proton", "op3": "electron and proton", "op4": "electron and neutron", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Within an atom, the nucleus when compared to the extra nuclear part is", "op1": "bigger in volume and heavier in mass", "op2": "smaller in volume but heavier in mass", "op3": "smaller in volume and lighter in mass", "op4": "same size", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "What would be the atomic number of the element in whose atom the K and L shells are full?", "op1": "10", "op2": "12", "op3": "14", "op4": "16", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which metal was used by Rutherford in his alpha-scattering experiment?", "op1": "gold", "op2": "platinum", "op3": "silver", "op4": "lead", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "An element has an electronic configuration of 2, 8, 7. Its valency is", "op1": "2", "op2": "7", "op3": "3", "op4": "1", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "During a chemical reaction, atomic number", "op1": "changes", "op2": "remains same", "op3": "changes and then is restored", "op4": "changes alternately", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which isotope of hydrogen contains only one proton and no neutron in its nucleus?", "op1": "protium", "op2": "deuterium", "op3": "tritium", "op4": "None of the above", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Who of the following was awarded the Nobel Prize for his measurement of elementary electronic charge?", "op1": "Rutherford", "op2": "Robert Millikan", "op3": "James Chadwick", "op4": "JJ Thomson", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "How are the subshells in an atom labelled?", "op1": "s, p, d, f, g", "op2": "s, p, f, g, d", "op3": "s, f, g, d, f", "op4": "s, d, g, p, f", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "The isotopes of neutral atoms of an element differ in", "op1": "Atomic number", "op2": "Mass number", "op3": "Number of electrons", "op4": "Chemical properties", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "The electronic configuration of an atom having atomic number 20 is", "op1": "2, 8, 8, 2", "op2": "2, 8, 10", "op3": "2, 6, 8, 4", "op4": "2, 4, 8, 6", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Almost the entire mass of an atom is concentrated in the", "op1": "proton", "op2": "electrons", "op3": "nucleus", "op4": "neutrons", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "The proton is heavier than an electron by", "op1": "187 times", "op2": "1837 times", "op3": "3837 times", "op4": "2827 times", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which of the following is true about a charged atom?", "op1": "anion is negatively charged", "op2": "cation is negatively charged", "op3": "cation has gained an electron", "op4": "anion has lost an electron", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which of the following is not a fundamental particle?", "op1": "Proton", "op2": "Neutron", "op3": "Alpha particle", "op4": "Electron", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which one among the following most correctly determines the atomic number of an element?", "op1": "Number of protons", "op2": "Number of protons and electrons", "op3": "Number of ions", "op4": "Number of nucleons", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Which of the following is the correct electronic configuration of Nickel with an atomic number 28?", "op1": "1s2 2s2 2p4 3s2 3p8 3d10", "op2": "1s2 2s2 2p6 3s2 3p6 3d10", "op3": "1s2 2s2 2p4 3s2 3p6 3d10 4s2", "op4": "1s2 2s2 2p6 3s2 3p6 3d8 4s2", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "How many electrons does the outermost shell of neon have?", "op1": "4", "op2": "8", "op3": "2", "op4": "16", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which of the following determines the chemical properties of an element?", "op1": "Number of electrons", "op2": "Number of neutrons", "op3": "Number of protons", "op4": "All of the above", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "The number of protons in a negatively charged atom (anion) is", "op1": "more than the atomic number of the element", "op2": "less than the atomic number of the element", "op3": "more than the number of electrons in the atom", "op4": "less than the number of electrons in the atom", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Atoms which have same mass number but different atomic number are called", "op1": "isotopes", "op2": "isomers", "op3": "isotones", "op4": "isobars", "Answer": 1}]}